<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TLA+ Foundation</title><link>https://foundation.tlapl.us/index.html</link><description>Goals of the Foundation The TLA+ Foundation (TLAF) is an independent, non-profit organization dedicated to fostering the adoption of the TLA+ specification language in industry, academia, and education, guided by the overall goal of advancing the mathematical thinking in software engineering. The TLAF funds development related to TLA+ to broaden its use and facilitate a thriving TLA+ community, encouraging cooperation among members of that community.
See the TLA+ Foundation Charter and the TLA+ Technical Charter for more details.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://foundation.tlapl.us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TLA+ Blog</title><link>https://foundation.tlapl.us/blog/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://foundation.tlapl.us/blog/index.html</guid><description>April 2025 Monthly Development UpdateThis is the TLA⁺ Foundation monthly development update (subscribe via RSS). Here we summarize the past month of development for the benefit of Foundation patrons and interested members of the community. We will also highlight a good bug or small feature for prospective new contributors to look at! If your TLA⁺ contribution was missed, worry not - we publish monthly, so it’s easy to hop on the next train; open an issue here.</description></item><item><title>TLA+ Foundation Grants</title><link>https://foundation.tlapl.us/grants/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 15:18:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://foundation.tlapl.us/grants/index.html</guid><description>TLA+ Foundation Grant Program Call for ProposalsThe 2025 TLA+ Foundation Grant Program is aimed at advancing the state of the art in the TLA+ specification and fostering the experience of using TLA+ in research and industry. Depending on the scope of proposed work, grants may range from USD$1000 to USD$100,000. Applicants who receive grants are expected to complete their work within one year, though exceptions may be made on a case-by-case basis.</description></item></channel></rss>